yle M Johnson

(206)794-7417 johnsk01@uw.edu danceanddata.com @kylematthewjohnson



ABOUT ME

I am a former professional dancer with a newfound passion for computer science who is excited to transition from academia to industry. From my dance career I bring creativity, a strong work ethic, leadership experience, and practice working on a team. From my marketing career I bring an understanding of strategic planning and end-to-end project management. From my academic career I bring technical experience with programming languages including Java, Python, SQL, and R, and skills gained from coursework focused in data science. I am adaptable, learn quickly, and never back down from a challenge.



EDUCATION

BS in Computer Science

UNIVERSITY OF WASHINGTON

Coursework: Software Design, Data Structures, Data Management, Data Visualization, Natural Language Processing, Database Systems Internals*, Software Engineering*, Statistics for Data Science* *in progress

Associate of Science SEATTLE CENTRAL COLLEGE

9/2017 - 12/2018 **GPA**: 3.96 / 4.0



EXPERIENCE

Ballet Master / Marketing Director

CITY OPERA BALLET

Oversaw the redesign of the company's marketing strategy, introducing new methods of data collection to track audience engagement and ROI. My tenure saw increased audience attendance culminating in the company's most highly attended show in 10 years

Marketing Director

10/2015 - 10/2016

7/2016 - 10/2017

1/2019 - present

GPA: 3.61 / 4.0

TACOMA CITY BALLET

Expanded company marketing strategy from print to digital media, doubling the company's social media following and increasing annual ticket sales by 25%

9/2007 - 4/2018 Dancer

FREELANCE

Whim W'Him, Seattle Opera, Village Theatre, City Opera Ballet, and many more



PROJECTS

ML OPTIMIZED CC COOKIES

Combining my passion for computer science with my love of baking, I transformed toprated CC cookie recipes scraped from allrecipes.com into normalized vectors and applied Kmeans clustering to create two optimized CC cookie recipes

DANCE. MEET DATA

Used python with pandas, numpy, and matplotlib to clean City Opera Ballet's ticket sales data and create visualizations for analysis to optimize the company's marketing budget



LANGUAGES: Python, Java, SQL, R, LaTeX, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, D3

TOOLS: IntelliJ, PyCharm, Git VC, Jupyter Notebook, RStudio, Tableau, Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services, Google Cloud Platform, Adobe Creative Suite